♪ It seems today that all you see ♪
♪ Is violence in movies and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those good old-fashioned values ♪
♪ On which we used to rely? ♪
♪ Lucky there's a family guy ♪
♪ Lucky there's a man who positively can do ♪
♪ All the things that make us ♪
♪ Laugh and cry ♪
♪ He's... a... Fam... ily... Guy! ♪
Family Guy 10x06 Thanksgiving
播音员：现在我们回到Quahog
NEWSCASTER: And we're back with our coverage
感恩节游行的报道现场来
of the Quahog Thanksgiving Day Parade.
火鸡节快乐 Quahog
Happy Turkey Day, Quahog.
这里是Tom Tucker和Joyce Kinney
This is Tom Tucker and Joyce Kinney
在节日游行上的现场直播
live at the parade.
今天这里时不时地下点毛毛细雨
We've got some on-and-off drizzle here today,
所以我们有点湿漉漉的 大家也看到了
and we're a little wet, as you can see,
因为 显然 哪儿都没有遮雨棚
because, apparently, there are no awnings that exist anywhere.
这里的头条新闻就是
There's your top news story right there.
遮雨棚神秘的短缺使东北部地区受灾
Mysterious awning shortage ravages the Northeast,
而不可思议的是 2频道和6频道完全没受影响
but miraculously has not affected Channels 2 or 6.
别 别 摄像机拍那边
No no. Keep the camera over there.
我想让大家都看看
I want everyone to see it.
这就是为什么我们是千年老三
This is why we're third.
现在过来的是今天的第一个游行花车 Tom
And here comes our first float of the day, Tom.
主题是James Woods高中橄榄球队
It's the James Woods High football team
带来的"非基小调"
with their "Not Gay Revue."
♪ 我们刚赢了一场大赛 ♪
♪ We just won the big game ♪
♪ 狠狠地打 狠狠地上 ♪
♪ We drilled 'em and banged 'em ♪
♪ 狠狠地调教了他们 ♪
♪ And plowed 'em a lot ♪
drill bang和plow在俚语中都有性活动的意思
♪ 尽管听着暧昧不清 ♪
♪ And though that sounds suggestive ♪
♪ 我重申一遍没那个意思 ♪
♪ Let me stress that it's not. ♪
现在过来的是"飞天鼠与波波鹿"主题花车
And here comes the Rocky and Bullwinkle float.
一直都是游行上受欢迎的景…
Always a popular sight here at the par...
谁去处理一下
S-Somebody want to handle that?
有没有…有没有谁…
Does some-- does some--
有没有谁去处理一下
Does somebody want to deal with that?
汽车警报呀 还问"什么"
The car alarm, "what."
这人真是的
You're kidding.
好的 观众朋友们 再次提请您留意
Well, viewers, to top it off,
您收看的是5频道新闻车为您带来的现场节目
that's the Channel 5 news van you're hearing.
Phil Phil 把车门打开就好了…打开车门
Ph-Phil, Phil just open it-- unlock the doors.
你不必把钥匙插进去打火
You don't have to put the key in the ignition.
嗯 先把驾驶座一边的门打开
Well, open the driver's side first.
呃 我想可能是坏了 那好吧
Okay, well, I guess it's broken, then,
那我们也没办法了
and there's nothing we can do about it.
好的 感恩节快乐 Quahog
Okay, happy Thanksgiving, Quahog.
享受汽车报警声吧
Here's a car alarm.
好吧 我想我们只能…
All right, well, I guess we'll just...
唉 又好了
Ahhh, there we go.
肯定是Joe和Bonnie
Oh, that must be Joe and Bonnie.
大家都记住了 表现得高兴一点
Now remember everyone, let's be cheerful,
因为感恩节是他们的伤心日
'cause Thanksgivings are very hard for them.
- 就因为Joe不能走路吗 - 不
- 'Cause Joe can't walk? - No.
那是因为他屁股拉不出屎
'Cause his bum doesn't open up to poo anymore,
一个护士得在他有便意了之后
and a nurse has to go digging up there
帮他从那里掏出来吗
to get up after his stuff?
我的天
Oh, my God!
我知道
I know.
我也是偶然间听到的
That was told to me in confidence.
不 你不记得了吗 Peter
No. Don't you remember, Peter?
感恩节那天
It was on Thanksgiving
他们的儿子Kevin在伊拉克阵亡了
that their son Kevin got killed in Iraq.
看看这是谁呀
Look who's here!
感恩节快乐
Happy Thanksgiving.
咕咕(火鸡叫声)
Gobble gobble.
非常感谢你俩邀请我们来
You guys, thanks so much for having us over.
嗯 我们也挺高兴能再次招待客人
Well, we're just glad we can have people over again
原来那个堵门的大螃蟹走掉了
now that that giant crab's gone.
嗨 你们好呀 快请进
Hey, guys, how ya doin'? Come on in.
不不不不不不
No-no-no-no-no-no-no.
不不不不不不 不不不不不不
No-no-no-no-no, no-no-no-no-no.
绕开它就是了
Just go around it.
他不会伤害你们的
He's not gonna hurt ya.
绕开就好
Just go around it.
不不不不不不
No-no-no-no-no-no-no.
不不不不不不 不不不不不不
No-no-no-no-no, no-no-no-no-no.
不不不不不不
No-no-no-no-no.
好吧 试试从他身下钻过来
All right, try just going under him.
我想我们还是回家好了
I think we should probably just go home.
要不我们下次再来好了
Maybe we'll do it another time.
不不不不不不
No-no-no-no-no.
这怎么回事
What the hell?
妈
Mom!
妈 是我啊 妈
Mom, it's me! Mom!
哦 是的 一个小宝宝
Oh, yeah, it's a baby.
那是个大气球宝宝
It's a big balloon baby,
就像你也是个宝宝啊
just like you're a baby.
不 那个是我
No, it's me!
那个气球是我的样子
It's a balloon of me!
Peter 快来看这个
Peter, come look at this.
他看到一个宝宝 就想到自己也是个宝宝
He sees a baby and knows that he's also a baby.
真聪明
So smart.
妈妈聪明的小宝贝
Mama's smart little boy.
唉 你看Quagmire
Aah, check out Quagmire.
都过去一年半了
It's been a year and a half,
看来他对自己老爸的事还是耿耿于怀
and he still looks uncomfortable around his dad.
指Q的老爸在S08E18中变性的事
是啊 要适应挺难的
Well, it's a big adjustment.
毕竟 他老爸是做了变性手术
After all, his dad did have a sex-change operation.
那么 呃…您过得还好吧 爸
So, uh... how-how are things, Dad?
哦 Glenn 能回到这儿来 我感觉有说不出的好
Oh, Glenn, I can't tell you how wonderful it is to be back here.
这将会是一个非常特殊的感恩节
This is gonna be a really special Thanksgiving.
感恩节快乐
Happy Thanksgiving!
我们带来了鸡翅膀
We brought chicken wings.
哇 美味吔 我希望是那种无骨的鸡翅
Oh, yum. I hope they're the kind with the bone removed.
嗨 Carol姨
Hey, Aunt Carol.
嗨 Adam姨夫
Hey, Uncle Adam.
♪ La la la la la. ♪
别提昨天晚上的《天桥骄子》
Don't mention last night's Project Runway.
是一档关于时装设计的真人秀节目
我在自己的TiVo上看过了
I've got it on TiVo.
美国电视观众常用的数字录影机
感恩节快乐
Happy Thanksgiving.
我带来了小动物棉花糖
I brought Marshmallow Peeps.
哦
Oh.
好的
Okay.
我还想把那个耐热玻璃盘拿回去
I'm gonna need that Pyrex dish back.
好的
Okay.
现在就要拿回去
I'm gonna need it back now.
哦
Oh.
今天我不再想要别的东西了
I don't want anything else today
哪怕和我刚得到的东西一样赞
to get as tense as that just got.
Carol 见到你真好
Carol, it's so good to see you.
见到你也很高兴 Lois
You, too, Lois.
啧啧 这屁股可真好看
God, that is one nice ass.
- 谢谢 - 别客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
太好了
This is nice.
这真是太好了
This is very nice,
我们眼下在一起的时光
the time that we're spending together right now.
别激动 Joe
Easy, Joe.
抱歉 只是想到你们将来都要过世
Sorry. Just making mental memories
就不免勾起我伤心的回忆
for when you're all inevitably dead,
那时就我孤零零的一个人
and I'm left alone.
哎哟 Quagmire 帮我开导开导他
Geez. Quagmire, help me out with this.
不 他没事的 我是说 有时候
No, he's right. I mean, sometimes
小妞们也会死 那也不是谁的过错啊
chicks die, and it's not anyone's fault.
好了 大家伙儿 两点半了 该吃饭了
Okay, everyone, it's 2:30. Time for dinner.
因为某些原因 在感恩节 两点半是开饭时间
'Cause on Thanksgiving, 2:30 is dinnertime for some reason.
啧啧
Oh, my.
Lois 这些马铃薯看起来真美味
Lois, those sweet potatoes look delicious.
那是火鸡填料 妈
That's the stuffing, Ma.
戴上你的眼镜吧 别在走路的时候又撞到黑人身上了
Now put on your glasses before you run over another black guy.
这一桌看着真是太棒了
Oh, this looks fantastic.
我迫不及待要大吃一顿了
I can't wait to poop this out.
哎 谁会获得
Hey! Who's gonna get
今年的感恩节排泄王大奖呢
the Thanksgiving dump trophy this year?
- 当然是你了 - 必须是老爸啊
- You are! - Dad's gonna get it!
还能有谁呢
Who else?
太有爱了 有爱的一家子
Loving. Loving family.
好了 开动吧 亲们
Well, dig in, everyone!
- 你好 Ida - 你好 Brian
- Hello, Ida. - Hello, Brian.
- 过得怎么样 - 挺好的 谢谢你
- How have you been? - Very well, thank you.
他知道你的真身后 就吐了一地
He threw up when he found out you were a monster.
这顿饭真是太赞了 Lois
This food is so (bleep) good, Lois.
哦 是嘛 呵呵
Oh. Okay. Wow.
嗨 桌前还能再坐一个人吗
Hey! Is there room at that table for one more?
我的天呐
Oh, my God!
Kevin Swanson!
儿子 你还活着
Son, you're alive!
唉 我还熬了一晚上编了些死了孩子的笑话
Aw, and I stayed up all night writing dead kid jokes.
好吧 你猜怎么着 我还是要讲一个
All right, you know what, I'm gonna do one anyway.
Kevin 你先出去
Kevin, go back outside.
每个人都假装这一切没发生
Everybody pretend this didn't happen.
嗨 Joe 你最喜欢哪种做法的番茄
Hey, Joe, what's your favorite preparation of a tomato?
是不是番茄"圣代"
Is it son-died tomato?
恶搞了"Sundae"的谐音
是不是"死了儿子"的番茄
Is it son-died tomato?
好的 Kevin 你可以进来了
Okay, Kevin, you can come back in.
欢迎回家 小兵
Welcome home, soldier.
"死了儿子"的番茄
Son-died tomato.
Kevin 你竟然还活着
Kevin, you're alive!
我都不敢相信
I don't believe it.
我的天呐 真是奇迹
Oh, my God, it's a miracle!
呃 我想你取代了纯正的黄油
Well, I guess you replaced real butter
成了这桌晚餐的焦点
as the star of the dinner.
可我不明白
But I don't understand.
部队上说你在执行任务时牺牲了呀
The Army said you'd been killed in action.
究竟怎么回事
What happened?
好吧 这说来话长
Well, it's quite a story.
有时候 伊拉克的军旅生活正如你所想
In some ways, Army life in Iraq is what you'd expect,
有酷热的气候
what with the blistering heat,
无时无处不在的迫近的危险
the constant sense of impending danger,
还有那种同性恋士兵
and the one gay soldier
不自然地回避使用那个词
awkwardly avoiding the use of pronouns.
指美国军队中对同性恋的"不问不说"政策(2010年废除)
哎呀 我真是太想自己家里的那个宝贝了
Man, I sure miss my sweetheart back home.
我迫不及待地想回去找那个人
I can't wait to get back to that person.
开饭啦 小伙子们
Chow time, boys.
遵命 士官长大队长
Yes, sir, Sergeant Major General Captain!
哎哟 不必啦 小伙子们 这是感恩节
Ah, come on, boys, it's Thanksgiving.
叫我大队长就好了
Call me Major General Captain.
现在开动吧
Now you eat up.
我可不信任这些伊拉克人做的火鸡
I don't trust that turkey those Iraqis made.
哈 你紧张过度了 Swanson
Ah, you're all wet, Swanson.
我要白肉(指鸡胸肉)
I call the white meat.
我要黑肉(指鸡腿肉)
I call the dark meat.
我要这个用胶带粘在旁边的手机(炸弹)
I call the cell phone duct-taped to the side!
不……
Noooooo!
他们都死了 长官 除了Swanson
They're all dead, sir, except for Swanson.
他昏迷了 不过不大可能醒过来了
He's in a coma, but he's unlikely to recover.
那好 就给Swanson的父母寄一封信
Okay, well, just send Swanson's parents a letter saying
说他死了 因为反正也已经这么写了
that he's dead, 'cause those are already printed.
对了 干脆给我父母也寄一封好了
You know what? Send one to my parents, too.
我这五年的时间都呆在科威特的部队医院里
I spent five years in a Kuwait military hospital.
上周我从昏迷中醒过来
I woke up from the coma last week,
于是就直接乘飞机回来了
and I flew straight here.
真是感恩节的惊喜啊
Kind of a Thanksgiving surprise.
哎 当你昏迷的时候被性虐待了
Hey, when you get sexually abused while you're in a coma,
你是能够感觉得到
do you know it's happening
但却无能为力
and just can't do anything about it?
还是根本就不知道发生了什么
Or do you not even know what's going on?
这个问题我也很好奇
I also am curious about that.
哎 Kevin 你知不知道我在车上
Hey, Kevin, you know I put a yellow ribbon
为你们系了个黄丝带
on my car for you guys?
一个小玩意儿上面写着"我支持部队"
And-and a little thing that says "I support the troops."
因为没什么我不能为你们做的
'Cause there's nothing I wouldn't do for you guys.
可我现在没看到一点"改变"
but I don't have any change on me right now.
这个段子讽刺了奥巴马
好吧 不管怎么说 我儿子回家了
Well, all that matters is that my boy is home.
Kevin 我想让你见见自己的小妹妹 Susie
Kevin, I want you to meet your little sister, Susie.
哇
Wow.
嗨 小妹妹
Hey, little sis.
我觉着我这个做哥哥的要好好弥补一下 是吧
I guess we got some catching up to do, huh?
希望你别被吓着了
Hope you don't get scared
要是我夜惊症发作叫出声来
when I scream and have night terrors.
没关系啦
(à la Patrick Stewart): It's quite all right.
Patrick Stewart是《星际迷航》的演员 也在《美国老爹》中配音
我还见过更吓人的
I've seen worse.
人体蜈蚣
A human centipede.
真恐怖啊
How ghastly.
你妈妈和我为你感到骄傲 Kevin
Your mother and I are very proud of you, Kevin.
你是个战斗英雄
You're a war hero.
我没有觉得自己像战斗英雄
I don't feel like a war hero.
只有战斗英雄才会那么说
Only a war hero would say that.
哎 女兵们在那边怎么样
Hey, so what about the female soldiers over there?
她们能胜任吗
Were they able to contribute?
呃 你知道 她们尽力了
Eh, you know, they did their best.
要是她们中枪的时候
What with their regular bleedings
正好大姨妈来了 能够察觉吗
when they got shot, did they even know?
听着 大伙儿 我不是英雄
Look, guys, I'm not a hero.
我不想让你们待我跟以前有什么差别
And I don't want to be treated any different than before.
就因为你这么说了
Just that you would say that
我们才要用不同方式对待你
means we should treat you different.
来吧 大伙儿 咱们把自己最好的食物给他吧
Come on, guys, let's give him all our best food.
好了 现在你吃吧 然后咱们都出去
Okay, now you eat up, and then we're all gonna go out back
玩感恩节触身橄榄球——抱歉：
and play some Thanksgiving touch football-- excuse me:
是战斗英雄的感恩节触身橄榄球
war hero Thanksgiving touch football.
吔…
Yeaaaaah!
美国
U.S.A.!
我甚至都不知道发生过战争
I didn't even know there was a war.
好的 咱们来分队伍
Okay, let's pick teams.
我当队长
I'll be a captain,
呃 West市长 你来做另一个队长
and, uh, Mayor West, you can be a captain.
好吧 我选你当队员
All right. I pick you.
你不能选我 我已经是队长了
You can't pick me; I'm a captain.
之前从来没有人那样勇敢地直面我
No one had ever stood up to me like that before.
从那以后我就很尊重他
I respected him from there on out.
真是个好故事 爷爷
That's a great story, Grandpa.
我不喜欢
I didn't like it.
从前我的孙子没有一个
None of my grandchildren
不喜欢我讲的任何故事
had ever disliked one of my stories before.
从那以后 他就是我最喜欢的孙子
From then on, he was my favorite.
好吧 我可不喜欢那故事 曾爷爷
Well, I don't like that story, Great Grandpa.
未来的老人都会法术
Future old people are wizards.
好吧 游戏开始了
Okay, so here's the game:
我…我喝醉了
I'm... I'm drunk,
我要把橄榄球狠狠地扔在自己的娃身上
and I'm gonna throw the football too hard at my kids.
哦 爸 我们能不能…啊
Oh, Dad, do we have to-- Ow!
别哭 别哭
Don't cry! Don't cry!
你要是一哭 游戏就结束
Game's over if you cry.
我想让你体验一下生活 Chris
I want you to learn about life, Chris,
因为 生活就是这样的
'cause of, in life it's like this.
Peter 我觉着你可能喝高了
Peter, I think you may have had one too many.
也许该帮你醒醒酒了 是吧
Maybe it's time to ease off, huh?
你在说什么 Lois
What are you talking about, Lois?
老爹们在感恩节上喝醉
Dads getting drunk on Thanksgiving
那可是节日传统
is a holiday tradition.
我辛勤工作 才换来了桌上的丰饶之角
I work hard to put a cornucopia on this table,
源自希腊神话 感恩节上有美好寓意的相似食品
而你这个荡妇还要露出脚踝
and you're out showing your lower ankle
给路人甲 路人乙 还有村里的其他男人们看
to every Tom, Tom, and other Tom in our village!
早期欧洲妇女必须穿盖过脚面的长裙 清教徒在风化问题上更为注意
别拿穿衣服的事指责妈妈
Don't talk to mother in like fashion!
我受够了 看来皮带要派上用场了
That's it. The belt is coming off.
来吧 儿子
All right, son.
咱们来狠狠地打击一下那群菜鸟们吧
Let's put these bozos in a hurt locker.
怎么样 呃 "hurt locker"可是
Right? 'Cause, uh, "hurt locker" means
《The Hurt Locker》(拆弹部队)是描写伊战的奥斯卡获奖影片
跟战斗英雄什么的有关的词
some kind of war hero thing, or something.
噗 朋友和我曾经取笑过
Pfft. My friends and I used to laugh
那部不知有多假的电影
about how fake that movie is.
可是…
But...
哎 慢着 我 呃…
Well, wait, I, uh...
我清楚地记得那部电影上映
I'm pretty sure that movie came out
是在你昏迷之后啊
after you went into your coma.
对的…不 不 呃 我…我是说另一部电影
Right-- no, no, uh, I-I-I was talking about a different movie.
咱们去玩球吧
Let's play ball!
好吧 玩球吧
Yeah, let's play ball.
我周围的世界都变了
PETER: The world has changed around me,
我疯狂了 害怕了
and I'm mad and scared!
Lois 这个南瓜饼看起来不错
Lois, this pumpkin pie looks delightful.
哎 Kevin 我能看看你的紫心勋章吗
Hey, Kevin, can I see your Purple Heart?
美军授予负伤士兵的勋章
我真的从来没见过呢
'Cause I never actually seen one.
有一次一个流浪汉给我看了他的紫色的头
One-one time this homeless guy showed me his purple head,
不过从后面看 我…我不太确定
but looking back, I'm-I'm not so sure
那个真是军队里的东西
that that was really a military thing.
噗 我才不要那个傻逼勋章
Pfft. I didn't want that stupid medal.
你知道我把它怎么样了吗
You know what I did with it?
我把它扔回了白宫的篱笆墙内
I threw it back over the White House fence.
慢着 我记得你说过
Wait a minute. I thought you said
你从科威特乘飞机直接回家了
you flew straight home from Kuwait
在你从昏迷中苏醒了之后
after you woke from your coma.
你什么时候吧自己的勋章扔回了白宫篱笆墙里
When did you throw your medal over the White House fence?
不…不 我…我跟你说过 我先飞了华盛顿 扔了勋章
N-N-N-No, I-I-I told you, I flew to D.C., ditched the medals,
然后才回家
and flew home.
我想都是因为他那肮脏的民工鸡巴 是不
I guess that was just his dirty hobo penis, huh?
Peter在自说自话
Kevin 为什么你要那样抛弃
Kevin, why would you want to get rid of
自己的战斗勋章
your war medals like that?
因为那是一场愚蠢的战争 你知道吗
'Cause it was a stupid war, you know?
它所做的只是让我昏迷 杀死了我的一个铺友
All it did was put me in a coma and kill one of my bunkmates
让另一个终身残废
and cripple the other one for life.
等等
W-Wait a minute.
我记得先前你说
Now, I thought earlier you said
你的两个铺友都死了
that both of your bunkmates were killed.
现在又说只有一个死了
Now you're saying only one of them was?
可我只是想让你们知道
But I just want you guys to know
我只不过盯着那鸡巴看了半小时
I barely even stared at that penis for an hour.
看来Peter不太适应不当主角的情形
什么 不是吧 老爸
What? Come on, Dad.
无所谓啦
Whatev.
哎 这里为啥这么热
H-Hey, why's it so hot in here?
这里太热了
It's too hot in here.
慢着
Wait a minute.
Ed Hardy的T恤衫
An Ed Hardy T-shirt?
Ed Hardy是著名的纹身艺术家
这种二愣子专属系列的服装
That particular strain of douche bag
直到2007才流行
didn't arise until 2007,
而你那时候应该是昏迷中啊
while you were supposedly in your coma.
听着 别不依不饶的 老爸
Look, get off my case, Dad!
你到底想从我这儿得到什么
What do you want from me?
真相
The truth.
好吧 给你真相
Fine! Here's the truth!
我从来没有昏迷 行了吧
I was never in any coma, okay?
我当了逃兵
I bailed.
我伪造了死亡 然后开小差了
I faked my death and went AWOL.
我也伪造了一次死亡
I faked my own death once.
这个家伙不会再预约牙医了
No dentist appointment for this guy.
好了 就是这么回事
So, there it is.
我不是战斗英雄
I'm not a war hero.
我擅自逃离了自己的队伍
I abandoned my platoon.
那现在我们怎么办
So now what do we do?
我吗
Me?
我 我 我是不是该说点什么
Am-Am I, am I supposed to say something?
Kevin,
你因为涉嫌逃亡罪被逮捕了
you're under arrest for the crime of desertion.
我的天
Oh, my.
呃 差不多是我们女孩子该用化妆室的时间了
Um, maybe it's time for us girls to hit the powder room.
你可以在院子里弄
You may use the yard.
这么说你一直在跟我们撒谎
So you were lying to us this whole time?
你并没有真的在伊拉克受伤
You weren't really injured in Iraq?
先是Pat Tillman撒谎说他怎么死的 然后是你吗
First Pat Tillman lies about how he died and now you?
Pat Tillman是美国橄榄球运动员 被传在阿富汗战场阵亡 后经国防部证实死于友军枪下
Kevin 我不明白
Kevin, I don't understand.
没什么要明白的
There's nothing to understand.
我们的儿子是逃兵
Our son is a deserter.
走吧 Kevin 我送你投狱
Come on, Kevin, I'm taking you to jail.
- Joe 等等 - 现在不行 Bonnie
- Joe, wait! - Not now, Bonnie.
Joe 你不能这样
Joe, you can't!
Bonnie 我们稍后再谈这个
Bonnie, we'll discuss this later!
Joe 你休想把我的儿子带走
Joe! You're not taking my son anywhere.
怎么整的 你们要把感恩节毁掉了
Damn it, you guys are ruining Thanksgiving!
这可是我第二喜欢的节日
And it's my second favorite holiday,
就排在"假装不去注意人们的种族"日之后
right after Pretend Not To Notice People's Race Day.
哎 你看到Reggie了吗
Hey, you seen Reggie around?
谁是Reggie
Which one is Reggie?
呃 今天他穿了一条黄裤子
Oh, uh, today he's wearing yellow pants,
呃 黄衬衫 黄帽子 黄鞋子
uh, yellow shirt, yellow hat, yellow shoes.
呃 他还镶着金牙 呃 还有钻石耳环
Uh, he's got a gold tooth, uh, diamond earring.
呃 他还戴着一条大项链 上面有个美元的符号
Um, he's got that big necklace with the dollar sign on it.
呃 他在讲故事的时候
Uh, he's always grabbing his crotch
总是喜欢抓裆部
when he's telling a story.
就像那种发现了自己的老妈
Like the one about when he found out
其实是自己的奶奶之类的故事
his mother is really his grandmother.
能不能再说的准确一点
Could you be more specific?
呃 让我想想
Uh, oh, let's see.
呃 他总是用廉价的古龙水
Uh, he always wears cheap cologne.
呃 开一辆墨丘利美洲豹 仪表盘上画个皇冠
Uh, drives a Mercury Cougar with a crown on the dashboard.
呃 从来不付赡养费
Uh, never pays his alimony.
呃 他对不识相的人总是非常恼怒
Uh, he's extremely cut for a guy who never works out.
哦 他来了 多谢了
Oh, there he is. Thanks anyway.
描述的的特征显然是黑人 但在该恶搞节日下就成了白人
嗨 Reggie
Hey, Reggie!
听我说 也许我们应该让Kevin
Look, maybe we should just let Kevin
来解释一下自己的所作所为
explain why he did what he did.
一开始 我相信那出兵理由
At first, I believed in the cause.
可之后我就看到了我们对伊拉克人民所做的
But then I saw what we were doing to the people of Iraq.
无辜的人民
Innocent people.
有一个人我永远不会忘记
There was one that I'll never forget.
他是伊拉克街头的一个小男孩
He was a little Iraqi street kid.
几个月前我和他成了好朋友
I'd befriended him a few months earlier.
他应该还不到12岁
Couldn't have been more than 12 years old.
我教他如何说俏皮话 美国式的
I taught him how to crack wise, American style.
我猜那家店在"卖火"(大减价)
I guess that store's having a fire sale.
我跟你说 那小子有着与年龄不相称的脑瓜子
I tell you, that kid was strong-headed for his age.
聪明 但是天真
Smart, but innocent.
之后某天 有一场交火
And then one day, there was a fire fight.
我们搬来了一个在交火中丧生的平民
We bring in this civilian who got killed in the crossfire.
我掀开了布单子 这是谁
I pull back the sheet, and who is it?
不是那个孩子 可是 好像
Not the kid, but, like,
那个孩子的父亲的 比如 同事的邻居
the kid's dad's, like, coworker's neighbor.
他都74岁了 还能尝试干强奸的勾当
He was 74 and he had actually tried to rape someone.
可是看着那死者的脸
But just looking down at his dead face
想到他曾经和某个孩子的父亲的同事做邻居
and knowing that he lived near someone who worked with the dad
而我连那孩子的姓名都不知道 我就失去了所有希望
of the kid whose name I never found out, I lost all hope.
从那时起我知道自己必须离开伊拉克
That's when I knew I had to get out of Iraq.
我只能等待机会
I just had to wait for my chance.
我要白肉
I call the white meat!
我要黑肉
I call the dark meat!
我要这个用胶带粘在旁边的手机(炸弹)
I call the cell phone duct taped to the side!
不
No!
不知怎的 我在感恩节上逃过一劫
Somehow, I'd been spared that Thanksgiving.
可我不能说铺友也交了好运
But I can't say the same for my bunkmates.
他们的残肢碎体被炸得到处都是
There were bits and pieces of them everywhere.
我知道部队永远不能确认谁是谁
I knew the Army would never be able to identify who was who.
所以那就成了我消失的机会
So that was my chance to disappear.
于是我离开了
So I left.
你怎么能那么做
How could you do that?!
- 懦夫 - 叛国者
- Coward! - Traitor!
要是你以为我经历了这样一个夜晚
If you think that I'm gonna masturbate
还有心情打手枪 那你猜对了
after this tonight, you're right.
我们不必坐在这里听这个
We don't have to sit here and listen to this.
来吧 Kevin 咱们离开这里吧
Come on, Kevin, let's get out of here.
- 少来了 小贱人 - 值了
- Nice try, skank. - Worth a shot.
Meg以前就对Kevin有意思
那么 你离开战场之后去了哪里呢
Well, where did you go after you left the war?
头几年我过的很消沉
I spent a few years laying low.
写了一些诗 你们想听听吗
Wrote some poems. You want to hear some?
- 不 - 你确定吗
- No. - Are you sure?
充满了热情呢
They're pretty intense.
- 不 - 这样 我先读一首
- ALL: No. - Here, let me just read one.
要是我能猜出某一行的话 你能不能不读了
If I can guess a line in there, will you not read it?
我不认为你能猜出来
I don't think you'll be able to guess a line.
是不是某一句是 "冰炙热得像火一般"
Is it something like, "Ice burns as hot as fire"?
好吧 然后我就去了欧洲 澳大利亚 加拿大 哪儿都去了
Okay, so then I went to Europe, Australia, Canada, all over.
可我真的想念你们
But I really missed you guys.
我想和爱我的人在一起 无论如何
I wanted to be with people who love me, no matter what.
所以我回家了
So I came home.
好吧 我听着好像
Well, it sounds to me like
你是一个十足的Benedict Arnold Drummond
you're a regular Benedict Arnold Drummond.
Benedict Arnold是美国独立战争时的叛国者
Arnold Drummond是某情景喜剧的主角 Peter搞混了
他想让我们插入什么笑话
W-What's he expecting us to cut to?
我想他可能是要…我不知道…
I think he wants maybe-- I don't know--
戴着拿破仑帽子的Gary Coleman吗
Gary Coleman in a Napoleon hat?
美国著名的的黑人侏儒演员
可我们没有那一段啊
But we don't have that.
我们…我们得赶紧补上一段啊
We-We got to come up with something.
好吧 我们有 呃 我们有
Well, we got, uh, we got
"胆小的狮子做了Lindsay Lohan的妇科医生"
"The Cowardly Lion is Lindsay Lohan's gynecologist."
狮子是《绿野仙踪》中的角色 Lindsay Lohan是著名女影星
放这个 放这个
Play it, play it.
- 可他还没做好铺垫 - 赶紧放
- But he didn't set it up. - Play it!
好吧 我来检查一下她的病
All right, I'm gonna check her for diseases.
我只想请你们做一件事
There's just one thing I want you to do.
- 什么事 - 什么事
- What's that? - What's that?
开导开导我
Talk me out of it.
不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
那边究竟在搞什么名堂
What the hell is going on up there?
好吧 我很遗憾你们都从自己的立场上想
Well, I'm sorry you all feel the way you do.
可我只是逃离了一场不义的战争
But I walked away from an illegal war of aggression
一场发生在6000英里之外的侵略
being fought 6,000 miles away from our shores.
在那儿打总好过在这儿打 我的家业都在这儿呢
Better there than here where all my stuff is.
怎么着 你以为自己能让他们和911事件脱了干系
So what, you figured you'd just let 'em get away with 9/11?
Griffin先生 伊拉克和911事件无关
Mr. Griffin, Iraq had nothing to do with 9/11.
我们在伊拉克发动的战争已经杀死了五十万人
And the war we started in Iraq has killed a half a million
相当于发生了200次911事件
of their people, which is like 200 9/11's.
呃 看来我们为那些震撼人心的事件
So, I guess those moments of silence we had
一次次默哀的时候 你根本不在乎
at those sporting events meant nothing to you.
我只是说这场战争是不对的
I'm just saying this war is wrong.
儿子 你的任务不是决定孰对孰错
Son, your job isn't to decide whether it's right or wrong.
你的任务是服从命令
Your job is to follow orders.
好吧 纳粹士兵就是那么做的 对不对
Well, that's what the Nazi soldiers did, isn't it?
他们也是服从命令
They followed orders.
你是说我们的军队像纳粹一样吗
You're saying our troops are like the Nazis?!
不 我只是说盲目地服从命令会导致
No, I'm just saying that blindly following orders has resulted
上百万人的死亡 纵观历史皆如此
in the deaths of millions of people throughout history.
你知道吗 我整晚上都还没和Carol说话呢
You know, I have not talked to Carol all night.
Carol 你好吗
Carol, how are you?
听我说 我觉得你们只是急于评判Kevin
Look, I think you guys are all rushing to judge Kevin
而没有设身处地为他想一想
without knowing what it was like to be in his shoes.
他看到了恐怖的事情 在一场恐怖的战争中
He saw horrific things, in a horrific war,
眼下只有另一个人
that only one other person here
也许有相近的体会：Ida
could possibly come close to understanding: Ida.
她也曾在军中服役
She was in the military.
她也见识过战争
She's seen battle.
她也看到过无辜的人们被战争机器屠戮
She's seen innocent people butchered by war machines.
我相信Ida 比这里的任何一位
And I'm sure that Ida, more than anyone else here,
都更能理解和支持Kevin做出的选择
can understand and support the choice that Kevin made.
不 Brian 我不理解Kevin的选择
No, Brian, I do not understand Kevin's choice,
我也不支持
and I do not support it.
好吧 这就是个愚蠢的人妖
Okay, well, that's just some dumb drag queen.
孩子 当你上战场时 最终并不是
Son, when you go to war, you don't end up
为你的国家 亲人或者旗帜什么的战斗
fighting for your country or your family or your flag.
你是在为自己的战友而战斗
You're fighting for your fellow soldiers
他们在散兵坑中与你同生死
there in the foxhole with you.
你抛弃了那些人 就是最不可原谅之处
You walked out on those men, and that's what's most unforgivable.
你们知道吗 大伙儿 别提了
You know what, everyone? Forget it.
要不是今天 你们还以为我死了
Up till today, you guys thought I was dead.
好吧 我没死
Well, I'm not.
不过发生了这一切之后
But after all this,
爸 你可以送我去监狱了
Dad, you may as well take me to prison,
因为我现在巴不得自己死掉
'cause right now I wish I was dead.
如果谁还需要往馅饼上涂奶油的话 可别怪我了
If anyone has wanted whip cream on their pie, it's not my fault.
我在这儿竟然连一句话都插不上
I can't get a (bleep) word in edgewise around here.
Kevin 我不想再次失去你
Kevin, I don't want to lose you again.
可必须履行职责
But I do have a job to do.
走吧
So get moving.
这间房里至少要有一个叫Swanson的人
'Cause there's at least one Swanson man in this room
履行职责
who does his duty.
- Doodie是屎的意思 - 没错
- Doodie means poop. - It does.
是"duty"的近音词
履行职责吗 爸
Are you, Dad?
你真是那个唯一履行职责的人吗
Are you the only one who does his duty?
我记得可不是这样
That's not how I remember it.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你不记得了 是吗
You don't remember, do you?
我那时上一年级
I was in first grade.
有次你换班的时候带我一起去了
You took me out with you on one of your shifts.
我觉得那名称也太自大了
I just think it's presumptuous.
我是说 想想看 "乡村最好的酸奶"
I mean, come on, "the country's best yogurt"?
美国一家冻酸奶连锁专卖店的名称
有本事就证明啊
You know, prove it.
拿出数据来
Show me your data.
救命啊 来警察啊
MAN: Help! Police!
那人是小偷
That man's a thief!
快抓住他 老爸
Go get him, Dad!
举起手来 人渣
Reach for the sky, dirtbag!
怎么回事
What the hell?
对不起 警官
I'm sorry, Officer.
我…我只是给家人找吃的
I-I was just trying to feed my family.
我不管你想干什么 你违反了法律
I don't care what you were trying to do, you broke the law.
我知道
I know.
我真不知道还能做什么
I didn't know what else to do.
我要喂养三个大眼睛的孩子
I have three very wide-eyed children to feed.
大眼睛的孩子都是最饥饿的
Wide-eyed children are the hungriest.
孩子们 爸爸要离开一阵子了 知道吗
Kids, Daddy has to go away for a while, okay?
在你们妈妈明天死掉前照顾好她
Take care of Mommy until she dies tomorrow.
好的 爸爸
It's okay, Daddy.
你走了之后 我会成为家里的男子汉的
I'll be the man of the shack while you're gone.
呃 听着 有点误会了
Uh, listen, there's been a mistake.
我上这里不是来抓你们的爸爸
I'm not here to arrest your father.
你不是吗
You're not?
不是的 孩子
No, Son.
我只是来告诉你 你的父亲有多伟大
I just came over to tell you what a great guy your father is
他为了你们多么努力地在工作
and how hard he's been working for all of you.
等等 你放过我了吗
Wait. You're letting me go?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我也不确定自己做的对不对
I'm not sure I do either.
我知道法律规定我要逮捕你
I know the law says I have to arrest you.
可有时候法律只是一张纸罢了
But sometimes the law is just a piece of paper.
有时对 有时错
There's right, there's wrong,
对与错之间的 就是生活
and somewhere in between, there's life.
祝你们有美好的一天
You folks have a good day.
我永远不会忘记你所做的
I never forgot what you did.
哎 感谢光临 亲们
Well, thanks for coming, you guys.
你知道自己在那天所做的 爸爸
You know what you were doing that day, Dad?
你违反了法律
You were breaking the law.
你知道自己的职责告诉你本该怎么做
You knew what your duty told you you were supposed to do,
可是 你却做了自己认为对的
but instead, you did what you thought was right.
我有好多年都没想起过那家人了
I haven't thought about that family in years.
我一直想着他们
I think about them all the time.
你那天为我做出的榜样
And the example you set for me that day.
是我离开伊拉克的真正原因
It's the very reason I left Iraq.
我要那么早去工作真是烦死了
It sucks how early I have to work.
好吧 Kevin 我还是得说
Well, Kevin, I still can't say
我不同意你的选择
that I agree with your choice.
一点也不
Not one bit.
可我想有时候一个人
But I suppose sometimes a man
必须去做他认为正确的事
has to do what he thinks is right.
如果你认为那么做是正确的
And if that's what you thought was right,
我想我还能接受
I guess I can accept it.
很高兴你回来了 儿子
I'm glad you're home, son.
我也是 老爸
Me, too, Dad.
这里还有一些剩下的南瓜饼 大伙儿
You know, there's still some pumpkin pie left, everyone.
对我来说是好事啊
That sounds good to me.
我也是
Me, too.
祝大家感恩节快乐 哈
Hey, happy Thanksgiving to us all, huh?
美国 美国
USA! USA!
等等
Wait!
那人是个冒充者
That man's an imposter.
我才是真正的Kevin Swanson
I'm the real Kevin Swanson!
伙计们 我觉得好像没时间安排这个戏份了
Guys, I don't think we have time for this.
中文字幕: zurica 校对: wudixny 注释: zurica 后期: zurica 压制: zurica @familyguy贴吧字幕组